Aleksei Beliaev

Rehovot, Israel +972 585362546 beliaeff@gmail.com

About me

Senior solution architect with wide experience of creating and maintaining IT systems. Deep knowledge of C#, JavaScript, SQL, PHP and many other technologies; 10+ experience in Microsoft technologies. I've implemented a large number of projects on SharePoint (2007, 2010 and 2019) platforms. Developed applications both for SharePoint and standalone, integrated them with external databases and webservices.

Over fifteen years experience in programming and a Master degree in engineering makes me capable of executing complicated and challenging projects.

My family and I did Alia last year and I'm looking for a company to continue my career in Israel.

Technical Skills Set

- Development of environments: Asp.Net, C#, Java Script and frameworks (React, jQuery, NodeJS), XHTML, CSS, XML, DOM, PHP, PowerShell, Windows cmd-scripts, UNIX shell scripts.
- Development applications for SharePoint web-parts, timer jobs, web-services; MVC applications .Net and net.Core
- Deep experience with Databases Microsoft SQL Server 2008, 2012, MySQL writing complex SQL queries, creating stored procedures, views, optimization of SQL queries.

Experience

2008 – 2022 GPB, financial company

2015-2022. Senior Software Engineer

I successfully completed the Portal migration from SharePoint 2010 to SharePoint 2019 - 25k+ active users, ~1Tb content databases, about 50 various applications and customizations. I made a substantial analysis of the existing system, its infrastructure, applications and integration with external systems. I created a migration plan and then managed the process, also I developed and implemented several applications for direct data migration from SharePoint 2010 to 2019.

Automated the development process based on SharePoint 2019 and Net.Core applications with TeamCity, Bitbucket. Successfully leaded the team of 13 employees. Managed full stack development from receiving a task to a complete solution.

<u>2010 - 2015</u>. Full-stack SharePoint Software developer.

Full life cycle support of the Portal system based on Microsoft SharePoint. Collaborated with contractors to offer and then develop and implement different solutions. Integrate various features and technical specifications of applications, continuous functionality of the Portal system, developed SharePoint solutions for internal needs.

Developed an Employee information application (Asp.net, C#, MSSQL, SharePoint) with custom database, integrated with employee accounting system and Active Directory. Aggregation data from several databases, synchronous and asynchronous exchanges between different data sources. Created a number of applications that use SharePoint objects as datasource, custom web-parts for SharePoint.

<u>2008 – 2010</u>. Junior software developer.

Development of simple applications and functions for internal needs of the company - polls, photogallery, making promo-pages. Simple SQL requests and usage in web-applications.

<u>2007 – 2008</u>. Traverse avia service, air flights organization, Head engineer

Created and supported company web-sites on PHP and MySQL using self-made CMS.

<u>2006 – 2007</u>. Protek, pharmaceutical company, IT-specialist

Developed a multivariable search system of drugs in pharmacies in Moscow using PHP and MySQL, a website search system with multivariable filters.

2004-2006. RBC, Media company, Web-master

Member of a team of developers.

Education:

1998 – 2004 Moscow Institute of Radio Equipment, Electronics and Automation, Master Degree in Radio engineering.

Most recent courses:

SharePoint 2016: Administration (Microsoft); IIS 7.5 Administration and troubleshooting (Microsoft); Visual Studio 2012 ALM Testing Tools (Microsoft)

Hobbies:

Sports – fitness, snowboard, photo, arduino.

Languages: Russian (native), English (Upper Intermediate)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksei-beliaev-07044b76/https://www.facebook.com/alexeybeliaeff/